SUNYA Women's Club; Records ua901.001
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
SUNYA Women's Club Records
1951-1992
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany. SUNYA Womens Club.
ua901.001
2.0 cubic ft.
Records of the social and community activities performed a social group of faculty wives and other women that perfomed university and community service.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
These records were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany,by SUNYA Women's Club and its predecessors.
Biographical History
The SUNYA Women's Club was founded in 1951 by Virginia Collins as the Faculty Wives Club of the New York State College for Teachers. The club's purpose was to encourage the wives of faculty members to become acquainted. The club's name went through a number of minor changes. It was offically named the Faculty Wives Club of SUNY at Albany from 1959 through 1979 (commonly known as the SUNY Faculty Wives Club). In 1980 the club adopted the current name, the SUNYA Women's Club. Prominent club activities included sponsoring foreign/international students and helping them adjust to life in this country, organizing bloodmobiles, giving university tours, and providing volunteers for university activities. Social and fund-raising activities included running fashion shows and teas. The club also founded and ran a nursery (1951-66) in Brubacher and Sayles Halls open during club meetings. The club is now divided into ten geographical areas. Each of these areas has its own activities which aim at fostering closer ties between members of the university community. Current activities of the club include running a scholarship fund for one U.S. student per year, holding orientation for new faculty and spouses, raising funds for the Ann Lee Home by hosting a yearly fashion show, running bloodmobiles for the Red Cross, and maintaining a list of volunteers willing to work during university activities.
Scope and Contents
The files contain bylaws, committee reports, correspondence, membership directories and lists, newsletters, publicity releases relating to the club's social and community activities. The files detail the club's community activities which included sponsoring foreign students, bloodmobiles, giving university tours, and providing volunteers for university activities. Social and fund-raising activities included fashion shows and teas. The files are arranged in alphabetical order and chronologically there under by title.
The scrapbooks contain letters, membership directories, newsletters, newspaper clippings, and photographs kept by the SUNYA Women's Club. The earlier scrapbooks (especially the first one, 1953-1969) consist mainly of newspaper clippings with some letters and photographs. The last two scrapbooks contain photographs of the social functions. The scrapbooks are arranged in chronological order.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection has two series and is arranged alphabetically.
Women -- Societies and clubs.; Universities and colleges -- Faculty.; UAlbany Faculty & Alumni Papers; State University of New York at Albany. SUNYA Womens Club.; Faculty Wives Club of SUNY at Albany.; State College for Teachers (Albany, N.Y.)
- Announcements, 1960; 1968-1972; 1974; 1976-1978; 1983-1984 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 1)
- Brochures, 1971; 1982-1991 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 2)
- Budgets, 1977-1983; 1986-1991 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 3)
- Bylaws, 1959; 1966-1967; 1970-1978; 1980-1982; 1990 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1959-1968; 1970-1979; 1982; 1987-1988; 1991-1992 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 5)
- Membership directories, 1966-1972 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 6)
- Membership directories, 1952-1965 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 7)
- Membership lists, 1966-1968; 1973-1976 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 8)
- Membership lists, 1978-1992 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 9)
- Newsletters, 1972-1981 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 10)
- Newsletters, 1979-1985; 1990 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 11)
- New Faculty Wives Committee, 1956-1966; 1969-1971; 1972; 1974; 1976 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 12)
- Officers job descriptions, 1982-1983 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 13)
- Newspaper clippings, Undated (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 14)
- Past presidents lists, 1951-1990 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 15)
- Paid membership lists, 1972-1983 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 16)
- Publicity releases, 1977-1978; 1986-1988 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 17)
- Report of board members 1, 1951-1955 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 18)
- Report of board members 1 (cont.), 1955-1959 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 19)
- Report of board members 2, 1958-1962 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 20)
- Report of board members 2 (cont.), 1962-1964 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 21)
- Report of board members 3, 1956-1968 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 22)
- Report of board members 4, 1967-1971 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 23)
- Report of board members 4 (cont.), 1972-1979 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 24)
- Report of board members 5, 1975-1978; 1980; 1983; 1986-1989 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 25)
- Reports on nursery, 1952-1966; 1973 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 26)
- Service committee reports, 1954-1957; 1962-1963; 1975-1976 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 27)
- Zone reports, 1951-1958; 1963-1967; 1970-1979; 1982-1986 (Box 1 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 28)
- Scrapbook, 1953-1969 (Box 2 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 1)
- Scrapbook, 1970-1980 (Box 2 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 2)
- Scrapbook, 1980-1981 (Box 2 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 3)
- Scrapbook, 1981 (Box 2 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 4)
- Scrapbook, 1984; 1987 (Box 2 (SUNYA Women's Club Records), Folder 5)